<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on mberkow</title>
    <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on mberkow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 20:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mberkow.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/happy-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 20:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/happy-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>One year ago I resolved to begin producing on the internet. So I started an Instagram account to chronicle my attempts at making cocktails. Now one year and 83 cocktails later I&#39;ve grown my bar and my skills. But being a nerd I also had to pull some stats..
I&#39;ve made 83 different cocktailsThe most commonly used ingredient in Lemon Juice (31)The most commonly used alcohol ingredient is Gin (23)I&#39;ve used 33 unique ingredients not including bittersThe smallest cocktail had three ingredientsThe largest cocktail had eight ingredientsI&#39;ve sourced the most cocktails from Cocktail Virgin Blog (23) with Common Man Cocktails coming in second (13)I owe much of my inspiration to those two sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Audacious &#43; Nobody Noticing = Awesome!</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/something-audacious--nobody-noticing--awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/something-audacious--nobody-noticing--awesome/</guid>
      <description>I remember watching a documentary (or maybe it was Pushing Tin) about air traffic controllers who passed around small pieces of paper with flight information. As an aircraft would transition from approach to ground control to departure the triangles would be passed from person to person.
Last night my team moved 27 critical pieces of&amp;nbsp;equipment&amp;nbsp;that run our entire&amp;nbsp;business.&amp;nbsp;It took us countless hours of prep and five hours of execution. We needed a way to keep the entire company informed of our progress, coordinate three different teams and make sure our bosses had enough information to keep off our backs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warbreaker</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/warbreaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/warbreaker/</guid>
      <description>Warbreaker
Brandon Sanderson
But he&#39;d found that imaginary things were often the only items of real substance in people&#39;s lives.
pg. 159
Unknowing ignorance is preferable to informed stupidity.
pg. 311
After all anyone with a strong faith different from your own must either be a crazy zealot or a laying manipulator.
pg. 543
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goal</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-goal/</guid>
      <description>The Goal
Eliyahu M Goldratt
&#34;A bottleneck, Jonah continues, is any resource whose capacity is equal to or less than the demand placed upon it. And a non-bottleneck is any resource whose capacity is greater than the demand placed on it.&#34;
pg. 138
&#34;...when I was a physicist, people would come to me from time to time with problems in mathematics they couldn&#39;t solve. they wanted me to check their numbers for the, But after a while I learned not to waste my time checking the numbers -- because the numbers were almost always right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/steve-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 18:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/steve-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Steve JobsWalter IsaacsonSteve wasn&#39;t much of an engineer himself, but he was very good at assessing people&#39;s answers. He could tell whether the engineers were defensive or unsure of themselves.&amp;nbsp;Pg 100&#34;Steve had a tendency to look at vulnerabilities and neuroses and turn them into spiritual attributes.&#34;Joanna Hoffman pg. 263 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Care What Other People Think</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/what-do-you-care-what-other-people-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 20:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/what-do-you-care-what-other-people-think/</guid>
      <description>What Do You Care What Other People Think
Richard P. Feynman
&#34;That story was probably incorrect in detail, but what he was telling me was right in principle.&#34;
pg. 15
&#34;Your situation is just an accident of life.&#34;
pg. 51
&#34;They got all excited and began to describe the problem to me. I&#39;m sure they were delighted, because technical people love to discuss technical problems with technical people who might have an opinion or suggestion that could be useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely American</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/absolutely-american/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/absolutely-american/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely American
David Lipsky
&#34;Cadet sex is like a bass, cadet Ryan Southerland explains. And you know how a bass will expand to fill any space? Well, any space that is possible, cadets will try and have sex in it.&#34;pg. 86&#34;Dads hoist video cameras to their eyes, the one-armed salute people pay to the future: this meets the memory criteria, this is souvenir-worthy.&#34;pg. 143&#34;The corporation is composed of the patient cadets who understand that every chapter of life is also groundwork for the next chapter, that cow year is really and audition for firs tie year - that all the good striper leadership positions will be handed out on the basis of their performance now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-innovators-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-innovators-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma
Clayton M. Christensen
&#34;For instance, is a notebook better than a mainframe? This is an ambiguous question because the notebook computer established a completely new performance trajectory, with a definition of performance that differs substantially from the way mainframe performance is measured.&#34;pg. 9&amp;nbsp;&#34;Three factors - the promise of upmarket margins, the simultaneous upmarket movement of many of a company&#39;s customers, and the difficulty of cutting costs to move downmarket profitably - together create powerful barriers to downward mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Auction Debate</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-auction-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 14:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-auction-debate/</guid>
      <description>It has been the month of auctions. First a couple of good points from others:Great comment from sku on John Hansell&#39;s blog about how general collecting worksGreat blog post by David Driscoll extending the analogy to pop cultureWould have rather been known as a &#34;Whisky Fan&#34; not a &#34;Whisky Collector&#34; in story board from the Whisky Cast HDI recall a point Ralfy&#39;s&amp;nbsp;made about buying whiskey now and saving it for later when it will no longer be available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look Ma, I&#39;m on TV</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/look-ma-im-on-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/look-ma-im-on-tv/</guid>
      <description>Was going to title this &#34;Three times, Sold!&#34; as I won the auction for the Woodford Reserve&amp;nbsp;Four Grain. However, seeing as Mark Gillespie was kind enough to include me in the latest WhiskyCast HD&amp;nbsp; and WhiskyCast, I thought this title was better.
I paid a little more that I wanted for the Lot of two bottles of Four Grain and one of the&amp;nbsp;Sonoma&amp;nbsp;Cutter. I was surprised that the internet bids ran it up to over $300 to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2012??</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 19:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2012/</guid>
      <description>At first I was shocked when I found out that Whisky Fest (WF) NY would be two days over a weekend in 2012. Even though I went to Whisky Live NY this year WF is the singular event I attend to expand my whisky knowledge and palette. On one hand this scheduling change is a great sign. Two years ago the venue was packed. To their credit the WF team made the choice to sell less tickets while expanding the venue to make the event more comfortable for the attendees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2011 - Part III</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-iii/</guid>
      <description>Part 3(Parts 1, 2)Quick HitsKoval liquors were good. They suggested the ginger one would go well in a dark and stormy. Added to the wish list.I tried the Catdaddy Moonshine. Not sure why that isn&#39;t Gin but with corn as they were all heavily flavored. If a liquor is a distilled fruit juice then this was Gin but with distilled corn rather than distilled grain. I liked it but it tasted like I was drinking a flavored drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2011 - Part II</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 08:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Part 2
(Part 1)
One of the first timers was Breckenridge Colorado Whiskey. Sweet nose and very smooth. They said it was 3.5 years old but it tasted much older. Not from the wood character which wasn&#39;t there but it was much smoother than I would have expected. It didn&#39;t have the rough edges that you expect from a young whiskey. I didn&#39;t note the ABV but it must not have been that high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2011</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011/</guid>
      <description>Part 1
Once again I&#39;ve confirmed that paying for the VIP ticket is worth the money. I didn&#39;t purchase a VIP ticket as I was in between jobs. Waiting for the doors to open I realize that there are definitely people who show up thinking it is a great way to get drunk. Because I didn&#39;t have VIP I had to make sure I hit the right booths to make sure I got the dregs of the VIP only pours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealers of Lightning</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/dealers-of-lightning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2011 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/dealers-of-lightning/</guid>
      <description>Dealers of Lightning Xerox PARC and the Dawn of the Computer Age Michael Hiltzik (Alan) Kay observed, &amp;ldquo;Everybody has to be able to play the whole game. Each person should have certain things they&amp;rsquo;re better at than the others, but everyone should be pretty good at everything.&amp;rdquo; pg. 116 &amp;ldquo;In the course of one frustrating encounter (Alan) Kay blurted out the line destined to become his (and PARC&amp;rsquo;s) unofficial credo. &amp;ldquo;Look,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;the best way to predict the future is to invent it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microserfs</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/microserfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/microserfs/</guid>
      <description>Microserfs
by Douglas Coupland
&amp;ldquo;And once again, work is providing us with a comforting sense of normalcy &amp;ndash; living and working inside of coding&amp;rsquo;s predictably segmented time/space. Simply grinding away at something makes life feel stable, even though the external particulars of life (like our paychecks, our office, and so forth) are, at best, random.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 135
&amp;ldquo;The industry is made up of either gifted techies or smart generalists &amp;ndash; the people whop were bored with high school &amp;mdash; the sort of people the teacher was always telling, &amp;ldquo;Now, Abe, you could get As if you really wanted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey over Pesach</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-over-pesach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-over-pesach/</guid>
      <description>I thought I had posted something about this topic when I first heard about the &amp;ldquo;alert&amp;rdquo; over the summer. Apparently I didn&amp;rsquo;t so here goes:

Over the recent holidays I overheard someone in my synagogue talking to the Rabbi about whiskey that had not been sold for Pesach (I’m not going to go into the details of why that is bad, out of scope of this post). It may have been a reprise of an OU/AKO announcement[1][2], but with an added wrinkle that specifically Irish whiskey was owned by Jews and therefore would require sale over Pesach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does John Know</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/what-does-john-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/what-does-john-know/</guid>
      <description>My comment on this post
&amp;ldquo;Sourcing and blending are real skills &amp;rdquo; Indeed they are, and in Scotland they have a name for people who specialize in those skills: Independent Bottlers. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why companies are insisting on the Micro Distiller label over the Independent Bottler label. It isn&amp;rsquo;t as if they are mutually exclusive. At least then awards and tastings can categorize the whiskeys correctly.
Does the US have an Independent Bottling tradition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Journalism &amp; Integrity</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-journalism--integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-journalism--integrity/</guid>
      <description>Very interesting post. Is he calling out Mark?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Cast 236</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-cast-236/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-cast-236/</guid>
      <description>In Whiskey Cast 236 Mark Gillespie leads a panel discussion which begins by lamenting that there are some really good whiskeys out there that no one knows about. Without disagreeing with any of the reasons provided to the panel here is my own take.
Whiskey is a luxury product, combined with the huge selection it is only natural that the connoisseurs who taste everything will find diamonds in the rough. But for the average consumer they either aren’t available or they simply don’t have the time or the inclination to find them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Menorah</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-menorah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 08:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-menorah/</guid>
      <description>From the I got to get myself one of these department: Whisky Menorah. Of course I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I would fill it with Scotch. I think a &amp;ldquo;Fiery&amp;rdquo; Rye would do nicely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Whiskey</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/american-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 13:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/american-whiskey/</guid>
      <description>Is it just me or were there no American whiskeys on the Malt Maniacs awards? Based on the interview on Whiskey Cast they had Chinese, Japanese, Indian, and Australian whiskeys. Looking at the list I didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize any American companies. Do they not submit, are they not eligible or are they not good enough to crack an 80 score? The person being interviewed did talk about how Whiskeys from Australia are getting better and taste less like &amp;ldquo;Australian whiskey&amp;rdquo; than &amp;ldquo;whiskey&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here Comes Everybody</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/here-comes-everybody/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/here-comes-everybody/</guid>
      <description>Here Comes Everybody: The Power of Organizing Without Organizations
by Clay Shirky
&amp;ldquo;It is easier to understand that you face competition than obsolescence.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 59
&amp;ldquo;Two things have to happen for someone to become famous, neither of them related to technology. The first is scale, he or she has to have some minimum amount of attention, an audience in the thousands or more, and second he or she has to be unable to reciprocate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Team of Rivals</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/a-team-of-rivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/a-team-of-rivals/</guid>
      <description>A Team of Rivals
Doris Kearns Goodwin
Lincoln: &amp;ldquo;Whether this feeling accords with justice and sound judgement, is not the sole question&amp;hellip;A universal feeling, whether well or ill founded, can not be safely disregarded.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 206
&amp;ldquo;When he advised temperance advocates to refrain from denouncing drinkers in &amp;ldquo;thundering tones of anathema and denunciation,&amp;rdquo; for denunciation would inevitably be met with denunciation &amp;ldquo;crimination with crimination and anathema with anathema&amp;rdquo;
pg. 168</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meatball Sundae</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/meatball-sundae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/meatball-sundae/</guid>
      <description>Meatball Sundae
by Seth Gudin
&amp;ldquo;Oprah is a superstar because she has the power (the right? the expectation?) of regularly putting new ideas in front of people who weren&amp;rsquo;t looking for that particular thing.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 65
&amp;ldquo;Your job will be to convert that momentary attention into long term permission and then into action. The question, then, isn&amp;rsquo;t how you get Dugg. The question is how do you make stuff worth Digging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest 2008 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-2/</guid>
      <description>[Part 1]
When I first got there I made a dash to the Woodford Reserve table to taste the new sweet mash whiskey. It was pretty good. The nose is quite different than the previous Woodford products. The taste is a little on the heavy/oily side. The big difference is that you don&amp;rsquo;t taste the nutty notes that are typical of Woodford. This one has more of the fruity leathery taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A complex system that works is invariably found to have evolved from a simple system that worked. A complex system designed from scratch never works and cannot be patched up to make it work. You have to start over, beginning with a working simple system.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash;John Gall
Found here. Hat tip KJB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest 2008 - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-1/</guid>
      <description>There is a good reason for this being delayed. As usual my co-workers were curious about Whiskey Fest and I gave them my three cardinal sins:
Go with a plan. It is easy to get overwhelmed and boxed out if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you are after.Don&amp;rsquo;t get drunk. There is nothing sadder then seeing the drunken idiots staggering around.Whatever you do don&amp;rsquo;t forget what you saw, smelled and tastedWell of course I go ahead and violate rule number 3!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerds</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/nerds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 08:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/nerds/</guid>
      <description>Nerds: Who they are and why we need more of them
David Anderegg, Ph.D.
I wish I had read this book in high school. Would have explained things and made them easier to deal with. I suspect I have identified the thing that made me &amp;ldquo;different&amp;rdquo; but that is a post for a later date.
&amp;ldquo;Illness, then as now, carries with it the notion of lack of culpability along with the potential for cure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox of Choice</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-paradox-of-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-paradox-of-choice/</guid>
      <description>The Paradox of Choice Why More is Less
Barry Schwartz
&amp;ldquo;Moreover, I think the adding of options brings with it a subtle shift in the responsibility that employers feel toward their employees. When the employer is providing only a few roues to retirement security, it seems important to take responsibility for the quality of those routes. But when the employer takes the trouble to provide many routes, then it seems reasonable to think that by providing options, the employer has done hsi or her part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statecraft</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/statecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/statecraft/</guid>
      <description>Statecraft
Dennis Ross
(Thanks to Blaine for snagging me a copy)
&amp;ldquo;The lesson is this: if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you want, your negotiating partner will develop a vision that servers his/her posture in the negotiation but not yours.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 189</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einstein</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/einstein/</guid>
      <description>Einstein
Walter Issacson
&amp;ldquo;You have to remain critically vigilant.&amp;rdquo; Question every premise, challenge conventional wisdom, and never accept the truth of something merely because everyone else views it as obvious. Resist being credulous. &amp;ldquo;When you pick up an application,&amp;rdquo; Haller instructed, &amp;ldquo;think that everything the inventor says is wrong.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 79
&amp;ldquo;America is incomparably less endangered by its own Communists than by the hysterical hunt for the few Communists that are here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blink</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/blink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/blink/</guid>
      <description>Blink
Malcom Gladwell
&amp;ldquo;We like market research because it provides certainty &amp;ndash; a score, a prediction; if someone asks us why we made the decision we did, we can point to a number. But the truth is that for the most important decisions, there can be no certainty.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 176
&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; if we can control the environment in which rapid cognition takes place then we can control rapid cognition.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 253</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More time</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/more-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2007 06:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/more-time/</guid>
      <description>I guess this is news b/c you can now stay for night seder and go for a date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can you hide??</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/can-you-hide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/can-you-hide/</guid>
      <description>Been wanting to blog this from UniWatch. I actually think this is a good idea. This way the opposing team knows who to hit and who to defend. With all the matching lines that go on in the NHL it would be much tougher to sneak your top scorer on for a double shift. On the other hand for the casual fans it may be a heads up to pay attention to the star player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death and Life of Great American Citites</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-death-and-life-of-great-american-citites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-death-and-life-of-great-american-citites/</guid>
      <description>&amp;rdquo;(The plan should anticipate everything and then permit no changes)&amp;rdquo;
pg. 43
&amp;ldquo;Summing up the incompetence of the area, Dr. Dodson comments, &amp;ldquo;The present state of the neighborhood indicates that the people there have lost the capacity for collective action, or else they would long since have pressured the city government and the social agencies into correcting some of the problems of community living.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;
pg. 121
&amp;ldquo;By its nature, the metropolis provides what otherwise could be given only by traveling; namely, the strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death by Meeting</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/death-by-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/death-by-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I think people would just like to stick with one things for a while, and focus on quality,&amp;rdquo; he pleaded, in a way that suggested the complaint was his own, not that of employees at large.&amp;rdquo;
pg 22
&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Consensus is usually not achievable. The likelihood of six intelligent people coming to a sincere and complete agreement on a complex and important topic is very low.&amp;rdquo;
pg 123
&amp;ldquo;To make meetings less boring, leaders must look for legitimate reasons to provoke and uncover relevant, constructive ideological conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rats</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/rats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/rats/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Bill contended that the word exterminate suggested a permanency to a customer that was not possible to provide, while control more closely described the service provided.&amp;rdquo;
pg 98</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fear</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/beyond-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2006 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/beyond-fear/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In analyzing and security situation, we need to assess these agendas and power relationships. The questions isn&amp;rsquo;t which system provides the optimal security trade-offs &amp;ndash; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s which system provides the optimal security trade-offs for which players&amp;rdquo;
pg 33
&amp;ldquo;A terrorist is someone who employs physical or psychological violence against noncombatant in an attempt to coerce, control or simple change a political situation by causing terror in the general populace.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes and Egos</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/heroes-and-egos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2006 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/heroes-and-egos/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve changed the &amp;ldquo;blog quote&amp;rdquo;. Retiring the old tired mainstay and moving on to something more appropriate.
It take more than a little ego for some one to blog, assuming that your thoughts, ideas and comments actually have meaning. I was always struck by this quote from Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s the Dark Half. I was always able to relate it to the Stand. When any one reads the Stand or watches any of the disaster films I am sure they imagine themselves as one of the survivors not of the faceless victims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Franklin An American Life</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/benjamin-franklin-an-american-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2006 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/benjamin-franklin-an-american-life/</guid>
      <description>&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; he accused Proprietor Thomas Penn of &amp;ldquo;taking advantage of publich calamity&amp;rdquo; and trying &amp;ldquo;to force down their throats laws of imposition abhorrent to common justice and common reason.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 169
&amp;ldquo;At first, he was reluctant to guess what practical use might come of balloons, but he was convinced that experimenting with them would someday, as he told Banks, &amp;ldquo;pave the way to some discoveries in natural philosophy of which at present we have no conception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22nd Floor</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/22nd-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/22nd-floor/</guid>
      <description>Many people use the phrase &amp;ldquo;Catch-22&amp;rdquo; to describe a choice with no good options. But the true definition of the phrase is surprisingly captured by the dictionary.com entry:
&amp;ldquo;A situation in which a desired outcome or solution is impossible to
attain because of a set of inherently illogical rules or
conditions&amp;rdquo;
In the book the Catch for Yossarian is that to not want to fly means you are not crazy therefore not eligible for the craziness excuse for not flying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theodore Rex</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/theodore-rex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/theodore-rex/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Uncontrolled competition, like unregulated liberty, is not really free.&amp;rdquo;
pg. 88
&amp;ldquo;When quarreling parties are both in the wrong, and are assailed with blame &amp;hellip; they will do strange things to save their faces.&amp;rdquo;
Grover Cleveland pg. 167
&amp;ldquo;Roosevelt cared little for Korea, a little, impotent kingdom that fancied itself an empire &amp;ndash; and even less for China. But he was aware that the latter was potentially the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metaphysical Club</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-metaphysical-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2006 09:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/the-metaphysical-club/</guid>
      <description>Notes from &amp;ldquo;The Metaphysical Club&amp;rdquo; By Louis Menand (0-374-52849-7)
Page 14: &amp;ldquo;The abolitionists were not interested in reform. They were interested in conversion&amp;rdquo;
Page 26: &amp;ldquo;On [Holmes&amp;rsquo;s] view, successful people, like Morgan an d Rockefeller, just had a better grasp of social tendencies than unsuccessful people did. Everyone is simply riding the wave chance has put them on. Some people know how to surf; some people drown.&amp;rdquo;
Page 277: &amp;ldquo;Pragmatically defined, variations are habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Versions</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/three-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/three-versions/</guid>
      <description>There is a well known adage that three versions exist to any disagreement. What the first party believes happened, what the second party believed happened and the truth. As a corollary to this I have always felt that when it came to news from Israel by reading the Haaretz, Jerusalem Post and Arutz Sheva somewhere in the middle would be what really happened.
With my recent trip to Israel and the recent happenings in Amona I think this system is coming under attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bourbon Rules</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/bourbon-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2006 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/bourbon-rules/</guid>
      <description>So found the following YNet Article via Josh.
I guess this is one time when my bourbon preference comes in handy. As per US Law bourbon must be made in NEW Oak casks.
It is pretty funny that the picture they use with the article is of a bottle of Gentleman Jack which while not technically a bourbon still adhears to the bourbon standard but is charcoal filtered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prucha Yidden</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/prucha-yidden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2006 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/prucha-yidden/</guid>
      <description>When I was watching the Ranger game Saturday night the announcers were mumbling about some &amp;ldquo;Prucha Song&amp;rdquo; they played when Prucha scored a goal. So last night in between periods they showed a clip of their ice level reporter dancing to the song which they said was by a &amp;lsquo;70 disco band about Ghengis Khan.
Yup you guessed it: Yidden! Looking to download the torrent from last nights game to get confirmation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Israel Trip Part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/israel-trip-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 09:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/israel-trip-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Figured I would take advantage of my blog to keep a rolling record of my trip. This way when my wife asks me what I did I will have some way of remembering.
The flight was decent. Had a middle seat but that didn&amp;rsquo;t cause to many problems as neither of my row-mates were 700lbs old ladies. Slept through dinner and most of the flight which is better than last time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest---part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest---part-3/</guid>
      <description>When we last left you, your fearless hero was taking a breather after downing three shots is quick succession. Having tasted the new stuff it was time to visit old friends. First on the list was Heaven Hill. Notable for their 18yr Single Barrel Elijah Wood which I picked up after last Whiskey Fest and saved for a special occasion (the birth of my daughter). They were show casing two new offerings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest---part-2/</guid>
      <description>So once we were out of the Glenrothes session my uncle had to go meet a friend of his. This was accomplished fairly quickly and the three of us tried the Laphroig table again. Unfortunately they were out of the Cask strength that they were pouring. So we had to settle for the 10 year old single barrel. Not being much of a Scotch connoisseur I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest---part-1/</guid>
      <description>So to start off my return to blogging I present my recap from Whiskey Fest. I figure it will be 2-3 parts long.
The evening got off to a less than glamorous start. Experience showed that there was little reason to arrive early. Most of the drunks show up early and leave an hour later. So I met my uncle for a quick 6:30 dinner and headed for the fest. Walking three block across town in a driving rain was a small sacrifice for what awaited us so we stoically pressed on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World Redux</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/hello-world-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/hello-world-redux/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Back. Lets see if this blogging things works better the second time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viva Las Vegas!</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/viva-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2003 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/viva-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>Great trip, made even greater that I walked away with $50 from the black jack tables :) This was my first &amp;ldquo;photo trip&amp;rdquo; where my goal was to take as many quality pictures as possible. I took 200 pictures with my SLR and 250 with my new Canon S400, so far the results are promising. The only thing I regret is leaving my wide angle lens in the car at the Hoover Dam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Stretch</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/home-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2003 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/home-stretch/</guid>
      <description>Ah one week until vacation! I&amp;rsquo;ve lined up 8 roles of film for the trip. My goal is to shoot them all! Malka recently came into a glut of slide film and she has graciously lent me some. Now I have to get my dad to dust of the projector. And my mom complains we never throw anything away :) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frustration</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/frustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2003 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/frustration/</guid>
      <description>Boren&amp;rsquo;s Laws: (1) When in charge, ponder. (2) When in trouble, delegate. (3) When in doubt, mumble I have a shiny brand new machine under my desk. But I can&amp;rsquo;t use it b/c I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting for the video card. I guess I should be happy that I actually got my boss to sign off on it. Another dark cloud in a silver lining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week from Hell</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/week-from-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2003 09:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/week-from-hell/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had one of those weeks that seem to be made up entirely of monday mornings? Well welcome to my world. Still loads of crap to wade through and I&amp;rsquo;m shoveling as fast as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>