<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whiskey Fest on mberkow</title>
    <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/tags/whiskey-fest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whiskey Fest on mberkow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 19:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.mberkow.com/tags/whiskey-fest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2012??</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 19:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2012/</guid>
      <description>At first I was shocked when I found out that Whisky Fest (WF) NY would be two days over a weekend in 2012. Even though I went to Whisky Live NY this year WF is the singular event I attend to expand my whisky knowledge and palette. On one hand this scheduling change is a great sign. Two years ago the venue was packed. To their credit the WF team made the choice to sell less tickets while expanding the venue to make the event more comfortable for the attendees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2011 - Part III</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-iii/</guid>
      <description>Part 3(Parts 1, 2)Quick HitsKoval liquors were good. They suggested the ginger one would go well in a dark and stormy. Added to the wish list.I tried the Catdaddy Moonshine. Not sure why that isn&#39;t Gin but with corn as they were all heavily flavored. If a liquor is a distilled fruit juice then this was Gin but with distilled corn rather than distilled grain. I liked it but it tasted like I was drinking a flavored drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2011 - Part II</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 08:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011---part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Part 2
(Part 1)
One of the first timers was Breckenridge Colorado Whiskey. Sweet nose and very smooth. They said it was 3.5 years old but it tasted much older. Not from the wood character which wasn&#39;t there but it was much smoother than I would have expected. It didn&#39;t have the rough edges that you expect from a young whiskey. I didn&#39;t note the ABV but it must not have been that high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Fest 2011</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whisky-fest-2011/</guid>
      <description>Part 1
Once again I&#39;ve confirmed that paying for the VIP ticket is worth the money. I didn&#39;t purchase a VIP ticket as I was in between jobs. Waiting for the doors to open I realize that there are definitely people who show up thinking it is a great way to get drunk. Because I didn&#39;t have VIP I had to make sure I hit the right booths to make sure I got the dregs of the VIP only pours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest 2008 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-2/</guid>
      <description>[Part 1]
When I first got there I made a dash to the Woodford Reserve table to taste the new sweet mash whiskey. It was pretty good. The nose is quite different than the previous Woodford products. The taste is a little on the heavy/oily side. The big difference is that you don&amp;rsquo;t taste the nutty notes that are typical of Woodford. This one has more of the fruity leathery taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Fest 2008 - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.mberkow.com/post/whiskey-fest-2008---part-1/</guid>
      <description>There is a good reason for this being delayed. As usual my co-workers were curious about Whiskey Fest and I gave them my three cardinal sins:
Go with a plan. It is easy to get overwhelmed and boxed out if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you are after.Don&amp;rsquo;t get drunk. There is nothing sadder then seeing the drunken idiots staggering around.Whatever you do don&amp;rsquo;t forget what you saw, smelled and tastedWell of course I go ahead and violate rule number 3!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>